Andrey Tseytlin

Data Expert (Data Analyst / Database Developer / Data Engineer)

IT expert in the field of Big Data.

Major expertise: building company's reporting.

I can participate in one of the roles: Database developer, Data Analyst, Data Engineer.

It can also be a mixed role (as it usually is).

Strong system/business analysis background, so I enjoy being involved into the underlying business processes as well.

Share knowledge, contribute to company's data culture and data community (Data courses, guidance, etc.).

Work with heart. Love what I do.

Work History

2018-11 -2023-03

Data Engineer/Database Developer

Leroy Merlin, Moscow

On my position I successfully combine the roles of Data Engineer, Database Developer and Data/Business Expert.

My contribution:

- Developed company's reporting from scratch (for Customer Orders department)
- One of creators of the data-team in our department
- Creator, owner and leading developer of the PostgreSQL Database, integrated with Customer Orders' Applications. This database has become company's major source for all client orders' data (both for business-users and teams from other departments)
- Database development to create large datasets with complicated multilayer logics
- Development of BI dashboards (30+, using these datasets). These dashboards strongly affect company's business in Russia and its efficiency.

Contact

Address

Petah Tikva (Tel Aviv Area) Israel

Phone

+972536229311

E-mail

andrey.tseytlin@gmail.com

Technical Profile

Programming languages:

- SQL (PostgreSQL,...)
- Python

DWH:

GreenPlum

Processes:

• Git / GitHub

Tools:

- Docker
- Apache Kafka
- Apache NiFi
- Apache Airflow
- DBeaver
- Jupyter
- IntelliJ IDEA
- Microsoft Power BI
- Postman
- JIRA/Confluence
- Slack

Competencies

Reporting expert

Database development

E.g.: the orders' give-away ontime/infull dashboard not only represents the values but also shows the "hidden" problems of the whole customer order fulfillment process, so the stores know the exact part of the process with the problem and can alter their policy

- As a data-expert participate in creation of business logics (together with the leaders of business-units)
- Improvement of database performance (server architecture decisions, code optimization and review, etc.)
- Data integration (ETL pipelines) to GreenPlum (the data of several Customer Orders applications needs to be stored in company's major data warehouse)
- Contribution to company's data culture and data engineer community (DE courses, guidance, newcomers, etc.)

2016-04 - System Analyst/Data Analyst

2018-10

Sportmaster, Moscow

Product-owner and analyst of:

- 1. Customer Relationship Management system (company's inner CRM (Oracle Database + Java) processing customer claims, bonuses, orders, reports etc.)
- 2. NAUMEN system (company's Telephony application (creating scripts' logics, building reports, bug fixing))

Additionally: performed data analysis and participated in system development from the side of the Oracle Database

2014-12 - Leading System/Business Analyst 2016-03

Prognoz, Moscow

Product: state statistical portal

- Managed development of several modules of the portal
- Reporting Module: built OLAP-based reports (using the inner company's BI platform (Prognoz Platform))
- Overall product lifecycle management: from interview with business-customer to testing and presenting the result to the customer committee

Data analysis

Advanced analytics

Languages

Russian (native language)

English (Advanced)

Hebrew (start learning)

2012-12 - **Business Analyst** 2013-08

Video International, Moscow

Company specialization: internet advertising
Customers interview, systemization of requirements,
clear tasks for developers, testing, documentation
and user-guides, business-processes modeling,
data-analysis of the advertising campaigns' statistics

Education

2010-09 - Master of Science: Applied Mathematics And Physics

Moscow Institute of Physics And Technology -

Dolgoprudny, Moscow Region

Elementary particles physics.

Diploma based on the performance of project "ATLAS" (The Large Hadron Collider, CERN).

2006-09 - Bachelor of Science: Applied Mathematics And Physics

Samara State Aerospace University - Samara Applied Mathematics and Physics Information science

2006-09 - Second Higher Education: Language 2010-06 Interpretation And Translation (English)

Samara State Aerospace University - Samara